How long does it take?
还有多久能到啊
Which street are we in?
这是走的哪条路啊
Take it easy.
不是 咱 别着急
It's just
这 这不
a traffic jam.
堵车吗
The GPS is guiding us.
这导航导着呢
We'll be faster after the jam.
堵过这段就通了
I'm going crazy over here.
急死人了都
Well,
这么着
I'll adjust your seat back down,
我把椅子给你调下去
so, you can lie down.
你躺会儿
Nope.
不用 不用 不用
I'm pregnant,
怀孕了
so I may vomit
车里头晃
if I lie down in a shaky car.
放倒了 容易吐
Fine.
行行行
How I envy you.
我是真羡慕你
Three of you are
这一家三口
living a happy life.
其乐融融的
No need to.
有什么好羡慕的呀
I rank the last
一家三口
in my family.
我地位最低
If we raise a dog,
要是再养条狗
I'll rank the fourth.
我能排第四
Come on, seriously?
不可能
Wow,
一看呀
your family's
你们家就是
all about you, isn't it?
都围着你转的
Li Lin must be treating you
这李临师哥是不是
like a queen, huh?
没事老偷偷地照顾你
Look,
看把你伺候的
how comfortable your life is.
一派母仪天下的范儿
It's not all about that,
母仪天下的范儿
you see.
能偷偷伺候出来
You gotta give the guy
得给人男的
some face, right?
一点面子吧你
That's correct.
你要这么说就对了
Not doing anything at home,
在家什么活都不干
I must play it low to avoid trouble.
不得装孙子保平安吗
Hit the nail
要不说我得跟你
on the head.
多聊天呢
Why don't I have
我怎么就没你
your wisdom of life?
这人生智慧呢
I'm so regrettable!
我真后悔了我
For what?
后悔啥呀
For not treating Wanzhen well?
后悔当初没对婉真好点
My ex-wife, Wanzhen
我们家婉真
looks after
这辛辛苦苦地
a whole big family.
照顾这一大家子人
I shouldn't go back
我还回去去找人家茬
and pick on her.
干吗呀
I should learn from you,
我就应该向你学习
don't interfere with
家里边所有事
all the trifles at home.
是事都不管
After getting home,
回去之后
get along with her harmoniously.
就当一个快乐的捧哏的
Just like you do,
就跟你一样
eat humble pie big time.
往死里装孙子
I'm not like what you've
我也没你说得那么
just said about me.
能装孙子吧
You are.
挺能装孙子
Listen to the tone on the phone!
你看你刚打电话那劲
Well, it's...
不是 这
Pretty good.
挺好 挺好
I'm sure...
真的 我 我一定
Forget it!
行了 行了
Stop talking about me.
别说我了 别说我了
Lower my profile.
装孙子
Enough!
什么装孙子
Let's talk about you.
你说说你吧
I want to know
我就想知道你
what you were thinking.
当初怎么想的呀
Divorcing Wanzhen?
还跟婉真离婚
She could give up such a good job
人家放弃那么好的工作
to look after your parents
给你照顾老人
and children,
照顾孩子
do laundry and cook.
洗衣服 做饭
You ought to treasure her a lot.
你不好好珍惜
instead, you despised her!
你还嫌弃人家
Do you know how amazing she is?
你知道婉真多厉害吗
In only three months,
三个月
she regains her finance license
人家重拿金融执照
and returns to the investment field.
重返投资界了
Don't really
我跟你讲
look down on her.
你还真别嫌弃
Who knows? Maybe one day
搞不好哪天
you'll beg her by kneeling.
你得跪求人家
I get it, I get it already.
我知道 我都知道
If one day,
等有一天
I have no other choice,
真需我跪求的时候
I'll absolutely kneel,
我绝对跪去
regardless of the health of my knees.
我不会心疼我这膝盖
I'll kneel as hard as I can.
我会往死了跪
Till I can't take it anymore
我跪碎了它
Go for it!
加油
Well, at that time,
不是 我其实当时这事
I oversimplified the whole situation.
我想得特别地简单
My male chauvinism
我就是
is kicking in.
我鸡了个小贼
But I was also realistic.
但是我想得也很实际
If I worked hard
你说 我这么能干
as well as she did,
到时候她也这么能干
with no one
我们两口子
at home,
都出去干去了
who will take charge
那这整个这家
of the family?
谁管呀
We've old and young to care for.
咱上有老下有小
Moreover,
还有就是
I am a man.
你说我一大男人
If my wife is more competitive,
这老婆比我能干
how can I keep my dignity?
这哪儿能行啊
I must let her know
我得让她知道
who is the master in the family!
家里边谁是大小猫
Oh, how vulnerable you are!
你内心这么脆弱吗
Just fearing your wife might surpass you,
就怕另一半超过自己
then you hold her back.
然后你就遏制人家发展
Don't point it out!
不要点破嘛
You're being selfish!
你这是自私了啊
If you thought like that,
你要想要这样的话
why did you marry Wanzhen?
你干吗找婉真啊
Wouldn't it perfect
找个小鸟依人的
to find an innocent bird?
不就完了吗
I thought she was!
谁能想到啊
Look at her tiny face,
你说她这小脸
right?
是吧
She had me with her
一看就是
delicate and clingy appearance.
一小鸟依人的人啊
Who knew that
可是谁能想到
she would be so strong
这一放出去
after we got together?
成一大老鹰了
You deserve it.
那你活该
You just don't get her.
是你不了解她
Yes, I deserve it.
是是是 我活该
Otherwise, my marriage wouldn't
要不然怎么这婚姻就
have failed temporarily.
暂时失败了呢
Temporarily?
暂 暂时
Temporarily.
就是暂时
I'm expecting your reunion.
我很期待啊
Be at ease.
放心
You'll see my success.
大胆地期待
Giving her a little pressure,
你说给她点压力
she should erupt like a volcano!
你就火山爆发了就
But I admit that I deserve it.
当然 也是我罪有应得
Don't repudiate yourself utterly.
你也不用全盘否定
Wanzhen once told me
婉真跟我说过
you were chasing after her
那时候你追她
like crazy.
追得还挺猛的
She believed
她觉得
it was love.
那就是爱情
So, you've gained love
所以你在婉真这儿
from Wanzhen.
获得过爱情
It's only a trick.
那就是套路
Say that again?
你再说一遍
No, no, no.
不不不
It's... It's love.
那那 那就是爱情
Do you know how passionate
你说我当年追她
I was then?
我多猛啊
However,
但是
loving is easy,
相爱容易
but getting along is hard.
相处太难
I now fully understand it.
我现在是深有体会
Why can't I just
你说我怎么就不会
lower my profile?
这装孙子的事呢
I'm so stupid!
我太笨了
Why did you mention it again?
你怎么又提孙子
Shut up!
你给我闭嘴
The wisdom of life.
人生智慧
You are the great winner.
大赢家 你真是
Am I?
我智慧吗
Now I know why Wanzhen
我现在知道婉真
fell in love with you.
为什么看上你了
You're honest,
你坦诚
never disguising yourself.
不装
I'd rather be
宁肯做个
an honest bad guy
坦诚的“小人”
than a lying
也不做个说谎的
hypocrite.
伪君子
Am I right?
我说得对吧
My infallible class monitor.
我永远正确的老班长
Maybe.
再议吧
Here we are.
到了啊
Where is it?
这哪儿啊
Oh,
少
Children's Palace training department.
少年宫培训部啊
No, you've got it all wrong.
我去什么培训部啊
I'm going to the Children's Palace.
我要去少年宫本宫
Lv,
那个小吕
turn over
那个掉头
to the Palace.
回宫
Hello.
喂
Darling.
老公
The driver sent me
司机刚才把我
to the wrong place.
送错地儿了
Where are you?
你们在哪儿呀
Don't come.
你不用来了
It's finished.
已经散场了
We are leaving now.
我们都要走了
I'm here.
我到了
Where are you?
你们在哪儿啊
Mom, where are you?
妈妈 你到哪儿了
I'm at the place of your show.
妈在你演出的地方呢
Though I missed your performance,
妈没看见你演出
I must come here
总得来看一下
to see your performance venue.
你演出的地儿吧
Go home with your father first.
你跟你爸先回家吧
Mom,
妈
the show is particularly for you.
这是我为你演奏的
Thanks for your cultivation.
谢谢你的培养
Thank you, my daughter.
谢谢我的女儿
Give me a hug.
给妈抱抱
What a touching scene!
多么感人的一幕啊
The great pianist and her mother
伟大的钢琴家和她母亲
meet finally!
终于遇见
Don't record it!
你别拍了
Stop recording us!
别拍了 别拍了
Come on!
快别拍了
You're in tears.
掉眼泪了
It's the imbalance of hormones.
我这是孕激素不平衡
Stop filming!
你别拍了 别拍了
Jesus!
真是
Yunjie,
云阶
what a good scheme!
咱们俩这设计可以啊
Excellent!
有效果啊
Thanks for all you've done.
辛苦了
Thanks you, dear.
你辛苦了
Let's take a selfie.
拍个照
Come here.
来
Take a photo.
拍个照 来来
Hurry up.
快来
Give one to me.
这个给我一个
Yes.
对
It's prepared for you.
就是为你准备的
One, two, three!
一 二 三
One more shot.
再来一个
Ready?
准备
One, two, three!
一 二 三
Jing,
姐
the free-range rooster
这是我让咱表弟
was bought by my cousin
去人家家里收的
from his neighbor.
正宗的散养溜达鸡
Look at
你看
its claws!
你看那爪子
See?
看见了没
The color.
那颜色
Got it.
看见了
Whether this is a native chicken
这是不是土鸡啊
or not depends on its claws.
就得看这爪子
The free-range ones
这土鸡啊
are much more nutritious
可比鸡场养的那鸡
than rear livestock in pens!
营养价值高多了
I have another one.
我那儿还有一只呢
Mrs. Wu asked me to stew it
吴阿姨说让我炖了
and send it to Xin.
送到月子中心去给心心
Yes.
对
You're doing it right.
这样做就对了
Working in
你现在在人家
Xu's family,
老许家干活啊
you must treat
你就得对人家
them well,
一心一意的
understand?
知道吗
When you leave here,
一会儿走的时候啊
bring two bags of medicine.
把那两包药带上
The larger one is for Mr. Xu,
大包是给许老爷子的
and the other one is for Xin.
小包是给心心下奶的
Don't worry, Jing.
放心吧 姐
I won't forget it.
忘不了
I'll help you kill the chicken now.
我现在帮你把鸡杀了
I should go back earlier,
我一会儿还得早点回去
because Mrs. Wu doesn't know how to kill.
吴阿姨她不会杀鸡
No need.
不用
I'll do it on my own.
我自己杀就行了
Fine. Go back now.
行 你现在赶紧走吧
It's over four o'clock.
都四点多了
I should stew the chicken
我这炖鸡
for over one hour.
还得炖一个多小时呢
You can do it?
你能行吗 姐
Of course I can do it.
把吗字去掉
We've made a deal.
咱俩可说好了啊
I don't want to kill you,
不是我要杀你
but I have no choice.
我也是没办法
However,
但是呢
Your death was meaningful.
你死得其所
You'll make a great contribution
你为我们家人
to our whole family.
作出了巨大的贡献
I would like to thank you
我代表我们家人
on behalf of my family!
感谢你
Ready?
准备好了啊
I'm about to start.
来了
Come on!
快来 快来
Hurry up!
快
Sis,
姐
we're back!
我们回来了
You're back?
回来了啊
We're back!
回来了
Dinner's ready.
马上开饭
Jing,
大姐
let's eat some meat today.
今天加个肉菜吧
It's a reward for my mom from my dad
这是我妈得全市前十
for ranking among the top ten!
我爸奖励她的
What a coincidence!
正好 你看你大姑
Your aunt made so many
这做了一桌子
vegetable dishes!
这个素菜哈
Come here.
来
Put it on the table.
拿上来
With a balanced portion,
我们荤素搭配
we can live a long life.
长命百岁
How dare you
谁又让你
buy such greasy food?
买这垃圾食品了
Occasionally.
偶 偶尔吃一次
Is that okay?
行吧
No way!
不行
Let me show you
来 来 我给你们
how bad
看看 看看
Look at this meat.
你看看这肉
It's so tough.
干不拉瞎 柴了吧唧的
The chicken was fed with growth hormone,
这都是激素鸡
you know?
知道吗
Besides,
还有呢
there are too many
那个反式脂肪酸呀
trans-fatty acids,
太多了
which are so unhealthy!
你吃了很不健康
And how could you treasure such meat?
就这样你们还当宝一样
What a waste of money!
还花很多钱去买
My sister.
姐姐姐
Don't be mad.
你也别生气
We won't eat it.
我们不吃了 不吃了
Can I just eat one piece?
我就吃一块行不行呀
Just one.
就一块
No way!
不行
Not a single piece!
一块都不能吃
You are in the period of
你现在正是
physical development now.
长身体的时候
you know?
知道吧
The large amount of hormone
那个大量的激素
will cause appalling results!
你知道会是什么后果吗
You may become
你有可能
so fat that you can't
胖成这样
squeeze through the door!
连门你都进不来
Jing,
姐
I know everything you said.
你说的这些我们都知道
It's okay to eat it occasionally.
偶尔吃一顿没关系的
By the way, the trans-fatty acid...
再说这反式脂肪酸
Right.
就是
My grandparents
而且我外公外婆
both sold fried chicken.
都是卖炸鸡的
I don't think my mom and her sister
我看我妈 我小姨
are as fat as you said.
也没反到哪里去
Wash your hands.
你洗手去 洗手去
We'll wash our hands.
我们去洗手啊
There were not too many additives
你外公和你外婆
in your grandparents' era.
那个是哪个年代啊
Times have changed.
现在是什么年代啊
No matter how,
不管怎么说
you can't eat it.
就是不能吃
Jing,
大姐
it's okay for us not to eat it,
你不让我们吃炸鸡可以
but we need some meat!
你倒是来个肉菜啊
All dishes are only vegetables.
你看看你全素
Meng'an is pregnant,
梦安这怀着孕
and our daughter needs nutrition
孩子要发育
for physical growth.
她需要营养
I used to take charge of
我们家里面吃什么
what we ate before,
原来是我说了算的
so please make it nutritious
你现在要拿主意
if you want to take charge!
你倒是把营养跟上嘛
Not nutritious?
怎么没营养
How ungrateful you are!
我看你就是白眼狼
I'm not pregnant,
我不怀孕
and I don't need to grow.
我不发育
I'll eat it.
我吃
No way!
不能吃
Why?
我为什么不能吃
I ordered you not to!
我跟你说了不能吃
I must eat it!
我非得吃
You can't, either!
你也不能吃
Why can't I?
我为什么不能吃
I must eat it!
我就吃
No way!
不能吃知道吗
Darling.
老公
Calm down.
别冲动
Stop fighting!
不能动手啊
I'm not!
我没有动手啊
I just want to eat some fried chicken!
我只是想吃炸鸡啊
Is meat all you want?
不就是想吃个肉吗
Does it deserve this?
至于吗
What's the big deal?
有什么了不起啊
This morning,
我今儿早上
I asked Lanxiang
让兰香
to get me
从山里
a free-range chicken in the village.
给我弄了一只土鸡来了
It is being stewed.
锅里炖着呢
How could you slander me
有鸡汤还有鸡肉
if I made nutritious soup?
还说我不懂得什么营养
I've got my plan.
我那都是有计划的
You are so picky.
看你们这嘴刁的
Even eat this kind of meat!
都不知道吃什么好了
Mom,
妈
I want fried chicken.
我想吃炸鸡
Forget about it.
你行了
The free-range chicken
土鸡
is also chicken.
不也是鸡嘛
Wash your hands.
洗手去 洗手去
Let's go.
走
What are you doing?
你干什么呀这是
So yummy!
真香啊
Yunjie,
来 云阶
both of you and your mom
你跟你妈啊
can get one chicken leg.
一人一个鸡腿
Have a chicken wing.
你来个鸡翅
I won't.
我不吃
I'm a vegan now.
吃素了
Well, I'll eat it.
爱吃不吃 不吃我吃
Meng'an,
梦安
how's the flavor?
味道怎么样
The soup is so delicious!
这汤特别鲜
Right?
是吧
The meat is
这个肉也
great!
特别好
Yes.
对呀
So chewy.
有嚼劲
Yummy!
香
It'll be better if it's fried.
要是再炸一下就更好了
What are you talking about?
你看你这孩子
I've told you
我不都说了吗
it's unhealthy to be fried.
油炸的东西不好
The free-range chicken
这个土鸡呀
tastes best if stewed.
咱就得吃原汁原味
Jing,
姐
ignore her.
不用理她
She's a bit rebellious.
叛逆了
Li Yunjie.
李云阶
You're way out of line.
你过分了啊
What?
咋啦
Strike.
全对
A full mark!
一百分
We'll look through them later.
一会儿咱们俩看一下
If you keep it like this,
长此以往
my dear,
闺女
you'll be a scientist
你离科学家
very soon.
不远了
You're at least an intellectual.
你好歹也是个知识分子
You don't sound like one!
说话严谨点
The joke is not funny.
这个玩笑不好笑啊
Fine.
行了
Yunjie,
云阶
let me comb your hair.
妈给你梳个头啊
For what?
梳什么头啊
It's late at night.
大晚上的
Why are you wearing my hair clip?
你干吗戴我的发卡呀
Because you look pretty
我就觉得那天
when you wore it that day.
你戴着挺好看的
I want to have a try.
我就想试了试
Do you need any favor?
那你还有啥要干的
Let me help you.
妈帮你啊
I want to eat fried chicken.
我想吃炸鸡
Or barbecue!
烤肉也行
It's... too difficult.
这 太难了吧
Is it true that we can't eat
是不是只要我大姑在
any fried chicken or barbecue
咱们家就和炸鸡和烤肉
as long as she's here?
绝缘了呀
Don't be sad.
别难过
Let's eat outside.
妈带你去外边吃
If we eat them
咱们去店里吃
in the cafeteria,
吃完了再回来
your aunt won't know it.
你大姑肯定不知道
We can also
最多
go for a walk to disperse the flavor.
再出去散散味什么的
Right.
对呀
We can also go to the nanny's home
还可以去外婆家吃
to eat the fried chicken made by her!
让外婆给咱做炸鸡
And barbecue!
还有烤肉
I'm getting hungry.
越说越饿了
Yunjie,
云阶
where is the chocolate I gave you?
我给你的巧克力呢
You want it?
你要吃啊
Chicken legs are yours,
鸡腿分你俩了
but I didn't even drink the soup,
汤也没喝上
or any chicken skin!
连块鸡皮都没给我剩下
Where's the chocolate?
巧克力呢
Behind the computer.
电脑后头
A good hide!
挺会藏啊
May I have a bar of it?
能给我一块吗
Chocolate can't compare to chicken!
巧克力哪有鸡腿好吃呀
How tasty the leg is!
鸡腿多香呀
So chewy!
多有嚼头啊
I'll give you a bar.
给你一块吧
I know you are the best.
我就知道你最好了
A yellow one?
黄的
There are different colors.
还有不同颜色的
Different flavors?
是味道不一样吗
Fine.
行行行
What else?
还有什么
It's a reward for you to have one.
你能分到一块就不错了
Chickpea!
鹰嘴豆
I want that flavor.
我要吃鹰嘴豆的
That's enough.
可以了 差不多了
Only two bars left.
就剩两块了
Well,
不是
we can still buy it.
吃完了再买嘛
Who will buy it?
谁买
I will.
我买
Two boxes.
两盒
Three boxes.
三盒
Fine.
行
Why can't I tear it open?
这怎么还打不开呢
Can't compete with chicken.
没鸡腿香
That's called life!
这才是人间哪
Better than the chicken?
比鸡腿强吧
Yummy.
好吃
Stopped vomiting?
不孕吐啦
Are you still stuck on what just happened?
这事还没过去呢
Or are you still sticking with it?
还是想再作一会儿啊
I'm gonna stick with it for a bit.
再作一会儿
Oh, I see.
再作一会儿哈
Here's the thing.
是这样啊
Under the effective nursing of Jing,
在大姐的有效调理下
I am now
我现在对食物
highly immune to the food,
已经有了很高的免疫力
but I'm still sensitive
但是 对气味
to the odor.
仍然很敏感
For example, today,
比如说今天
I smelled very
我就闻到了一股
strong perfume,
非常刺鼻的香水味
and I vomited.
吐了
What kind of perfume?
什么香水啊
I don't know.
我也不知道
It smelled so disgusting.
反正一闻吧 就特恶心
Do you know who sprang
你知道喷香水的人
the perfume?
是谁吗
Who is it?
谁啊
The woman who meddled with
就是把于海和婉真
the relation between Yu Hai and Wanzhen.
搅黄那女的
A mistress?
他俩好上了
No.
没有
Yu Hai swore to me that
于海 拍着胸脯跟我说
nothing happened to them.
他俩一点关系都没有
But I didn't trust him.
但是我不信啊
How could it be possible?
这怎么可能呢
The perfume was spread
于海车上
all over his car,
都是那女的香水味
and before he talked to me,
而且他跟我说话的时候
he asked the driver to wear earbuds.
让司机把耳机戴上
Think about it.
你想
If his driver,
司机
accompanying him every day,
这么贴身的关系
can't be trusted by Yu Hai,
都不是他自己人
how can I trust him?
这怎么可能没关系
Who buys it?
谁信呢
Well,
不是的
you've told me
你都说了
he asked the driver
他让司机
to wear the earbuds,
都把耳机都戴上了
which means nothing happened.
那就肯定是没关系嘛
Yes.
对
I noticed men
我发现你们男同志
are so tolerable to other men!
对同胞的评价很宽容啊
Isn't it way too much?
作过了吧
Talk in a good way.
好好说
Speak nicely?
好好说呀
Okay.
行
Yu Hai...
于海
Don't you think you were
你对大姐的那个态度
too hard
是不是有点
to Jing?
太那什么了
I indeed had a bad attitude.
不是我态度不好
You've seen it all.
你都看见了
But she was not like that.
她以前不这样
She disciplined me,
她也管我
but in a different way.
但是不是这样
How disturbing she is
这一点就着
to erupt like a volcano?
多烦人呢
I don't really care,
我倒没什么
but I'm afraid you'll be disturbed.
我是怕你们烦她
It's true that our life
我们倒也还真
is not as free as before.
的是没那么舒服了
Right?
对吧
Then what's going on?
那是怎么回事呢
What a drastic change!
变化这么大
How old is Jing?
大姐多大岁数了
Fifty-five.
五十五
Menopause?
更年期了吧
When I searched menopause,
我之前查更年期的时候
I recalled quite clearly what it said.
那上面写得可挺清楚的
Irritable, depressed,
易怒 暴躁 抑郁
sweating, and insomnia.
盗汗 失眠
She seems to have them all,
好像都有
doesn't she?
是不是
No wonder.
那就难怪了
It must be not easy for her.
那可真是太不容易了
We should treat her even better.
那咱更得对她好点了
Comfort her now and then,
你得哄着她
understand?
知道吗
During menopause,
更年期这段时间
if she becomes depressed
如果要是抑郁了
and don't get better,
过不去了
she'll continue to be depressed
她后边几十年
for the rest of her life,
都会这样的
you know?
知道吗
Besides,
还有
throw the fried chicken away
你赶快去把那桶炸鸡
right now.
给我扔了
Jing is a food saver.
大姐是个会过日子的
Though we're not allowed to eat it,
她不让咱们吃
she won't throw it away.
她也不会扔的
She may eat it alone
没准明天咱们一出门
if all of us get out
她自个儿一个人
tomorrow.
就都吃了
You're right.
对对对
Okay.
好
Menopause comes silently
这更年期 说来就来
without any signs at all?
连个招呼都不打吗
Dump it all!
全给它倒了 全倒了
Not a single piece!
一点都不剩
Jing.
姐
What are you doing?
干吗呢
Throw it away.
倒垃圾啊
It's not healthy.
垃圾食品嘛
No way!
不能扔
You can't! Give it to me.
不能扔 给我
It's not worthwhile
明天中午
to cook lunch for myself,
我一个人不值当开火
so it'll be my lunch.
还能对付一顿
Well, even if you're eating alone,
这这 你一个人吃饭
you can't eat unhealthy food,
你也不能对付啊
right?
是不是
Have some good food.
你得吃点好的嘛
Jing,
姐
do you come to my house
你上我们家来
to eat leftovers?
是吃隔夜饭的
You keep telling us health all day long,
整天还跟我们说养生呢
right?
是不是
Hand-shaking exercise,
甩手养生
and grain porridge.
五谷养生
It tastes bad,
这个不好吃
and it is unhealthy.
这个不健康
Didn't you tell us?
这不都是你说的吗
The leftover of fried chicken
那一顿隔夜炸鸡
ruins everything for health.
什么都打回原形
You are wasting
你平时那些
all the Chinese herbal tonics
党参啊 当归啊
you are drinking
什么人参 枸杞啊
every day.
都白费了
How can you call yourself a doctor?
你还是个中医呢
Right?
对吧
Do I spend your money on health?
我养生花你钱了吗
Even you are brought up by me!
连你都是我带大的
Don't be angry.
别着急 别着急
They're asleep. Keep quiet!
睡觉了 小声一点行吗
Jing,
姐
I'm in my forties.
我四十多岁了
My wife and daughter are at home,
老婆 孩子都在家里
so I'll take charge of the chores
家里的事情呢
at home.
我来管
Don't you worry about it.
你不要操这个心
I'm grateful for
你对我们好呢
what you did.
我心意领了
But...
但 但
Well...
就是
Don't make me embarrassed,
就算你给我点面子
will you?
好不好
How did I make you embarrassed?
我怎么不给你面子了
Aren't you making me feel silly?
你给我面子了吗
Who's the eldest in our family?
咱们家谁年龄最大
How dare you
你看你对我
talk to me like that?
说话这个态度
What an ingrate!
白眼狼
So heartless!
没良心
Jesus!
真是的
Jing,
姐
don't be mad at me.
别生气啊
I don't want you to eat leftover
我不让你吃隔夜的东西
because I care about your health,
是为了你身体好
right?
是吧
Well...
这
I have only one sister.
我就你这么一个姐
What if your health deteriorates
你万一在我这儿待着
for taking care of us,
把身体弄坏了
I'd feel extremely
那我这心里面
sorry about that.
多过意不去呀
Fine.
行行行
My brother-in-law
我姐夫最近
hasn't called you recently.
也不怎么给你打电话
Jing,
姐
you see,
你看
Meng'an's condition is stable now,
梦安这胎也算是坐稳了
and our whole family
我们家呢
has been getting even better
在你的精心调配下
under your management and
也开始有条不紊
meticulous care.
渐入佳境
and your treatment methods
您的那一套治理方法
have been grasped by me,
我也基本掌握了
so don't worry.
放心吧
I mean,
我是说
I think it's time for you
你要不要回去
to go back.
看一看
After all, Mr Ouyang is alone
毕竟姐夫一个人在家
back home,
是吧
and I feel worried about him.
我也不放心
By the way,
再说了
living separately
夫妻两个
for a long time,
这这 长期分居
the couple may face a marriage crisis.
这感情上会出问题的嘛
We're becoming old.
都五六十岁的人了
Nothing much can go wrong.
能出什么问题
Well, that's not the right way to put it.
那这话不是这么说的啊
Many problems emerge
有很多的问题呀
in one's fifties or even sixties.
那就是发生在五六十岁
Piss off!
滚
You haven't said a single proper word.
没一句像样的话
I said you were an ingrate,
我说你是个白眼狼
and you are.
还不信
Piss off!
滚出去
I wish you well.
我是盼你们好的
I don't want to see you anymore!
我不想看见你
Well...
我这
Piss off!
滚
Where were you?
你去哪儿了
What took you so long?
这么长时间
Isn't it mere garbage?
不就是丢个垃圾吗
I tried to comfort Jing.
哄大姐去了
Did you manage it?
哄好啦
I was kicked out of her room.
被轰出来了
How could that happen?
怎么会被轰出来了呢
How did you comfort her?
你怎么哄的呀
How?
怎么哄的
Just like what I did to you.
就跟平时我哄你一样啊
Like you did to me?
哄我一样
Comforting me for so many years,
你哄我这么多年
I've never kicked you out
我也从来没把你
of the room.
轰出去过呀
Really.
真的
It's the same.
一模一样地哄
I kept smiling,
笑嘻嘻的
with a kind expression,
和颜悦色
and gently told her
非常的温柔地跟她说
not to be mad,
你消消气 不要生气
and visit Ouyang if available.
有空回家看看姐夫
What did you say?
你说什么玩意儿
Now you see the problem.
知道哪儿出问题了
What did I tell you?
我刚才是怎么跟你说的
Menopause.
更年期
Irritable, and depressed.
易怒 暴躁
Comfort her in the right way!
你要哄你就好好哄嘛
She was so mad,
她现在在气头上
but you told her to leave.
你又说让她回家
Is that...
你
a right way to comfort her?
你这是哄吗
I'd rather reckon it
你这分明
as adding fuel to flames!
就是火上浇油嘛
If I were her,
她不把你轰出来
I would also kick you out.
她轰谁呀
Sorry,
失策了
it's my fault.
说秃噜了
I'll go again.
我再去一次
Forget it.
你行了
Don't go.
你别去了
There's no use anymore.
去什么去呀
Go to bed.
睡觉吧
I'll comfort her tomorrow.
明天我去哄
How couldn't you deal with it?
这点事都干不明白
How useless you are!
还能干什么呀
It's easy to comfort one's sister.
哄姐姐都不会
I...
我 我
Go to bed.
睡觉
Give me some space!
起起起
So disappointed in you!
这点事干不了
Jing?
大姐
Lin,
老公
where is Jing?
大姐呢
Jing sent me a message
大姐给我发了微信
that she's going back.
说她回去了
She missed her husband.
她想姐夫了
Do you know how serious
你现在知道更年期
menopause is now?
是什么结果了吧
Fetch me my phone.
去把我电话拿来
Hello, Meng'an.
喂 梦安
Hello, Jing.
喂 大姐
Where are you?
你在哪儿呢
I'm at the inter-city bus station.
我在长途汽车站呢
I miss my husband,
我想我们家老欧阳啦
so I'll visit him.
回去看看
Why didn't you tell me
你走怎么也
before leaving?
没跟我说一声啊
I'll give you a ride.
我好去送你啊
No need.
不用送
I couldn't fall asleep,
我呀 睡不着觉
so I got up early.
起得早
When are you coming back?
那你什么时候回来呀
During these days,
这段时间呢
I've noticed
我也看见了
that you two
你们呢
sincerely want the baby.
是真心想要这个孩子
I'm here to give you a hand,
我是来帮忙的
not to meddle with your life.
不是来添乱的
How's that?
这样吧
When you're delivering the baby,
等你怀的月份再大一点
I'll come back to help, okay?
我再来帮忙 好不好
Okay.
好
Have a good rest.
那你回去好好休息
If I miss you,
我要是想你了
please come back.
你可一定得来啊
Of course.
一定来
Okay.
好
Is she leaving?
大姑走啦
Is it because I wanted fried chicken?
是因为我吃炸鸡吗
It's none of your business.
跟你没关系
Can I take off the board
那我屋子里的牌子
in my bedroom?
是不是可以摘了呀
Don't you do that!
摘什么摘
Hang it right there.
在那儿挂着
It's your auntie's expectation!
那是你大姑对你的期望
Why are you mad at her?
你跟孩子置什么气啊
Isn't it your wish
这不是如你所愿吗
that she goes back?
回家看姐夫去了
Now, she's back
你这是彻底
eventually.
把她哄到家了
Hello,
喂
Song.
小宋啊
I was about to
我还正说要给你
call you.
打电话呢
How's that?
怎么样
How's everything going?
最近好吗
Hello.
你好
May I ask
我想问一下
how much money I can earn
我也有月嫂证
for a month
要是在这儿工作的话
if I work here
一个月能有
with a matron certificate?
多少钱工资呀
It depends on the level
那要看是什么级别的
of you.
月嫂了
Okay. Thanks.
好 谢谢啊
It doesn't matter.
没事
She's laughing
笑得呀
so happily!
真开心
Lanxiang is here.
兰香姐来了
This is chicken soup
这是吴阿姨
made by Mrs. Wu for Xin.
给心心做的土鸡汤
Xin is such a fussy eater.
你看心心这嘴刁的
She loves the soup made by Mom.
就爱喝妈妈煲的汤
Thank you so much
让你一天到晚的
for running back and forth.
跑来跑去的 真辛苦啊
It's my duty.
应该的嘛
Lanxiang, come here.
兰香 来来来
This is for our gratitude.
给你个红包
No,
不不
I can't take it.
这不能要
Meng'an has given hers.
梦安已经给过我了
That's for looking after dad.
那是照顾爸爸的
It's ours.
这是我们的
Take it.
拿着
For our gratitude.
小意思
Thank you, Mr. Jia.
谢谢你啊 贾总
Not at all.
没事 没事
Where is Xin?
心心呢
She went to see a doctor.
看医生去了
She's fine.
没事
A psychology doctor.
心理 心理
Is the company functioning well?
公司那边怎么样了
Has the financial product been cashed?
理财产品 兑付了没有
It's cashed partly,
兑付了一部分
but the rest has not.
还有一部分没兑付
It's promised
承诺的是
to be cashed in two years.
两年内才兑付呢
Do you think they'll cash it?
姐 你说他们能兑付吗
Can he give me the money
我跟亲戚朋友那么多钱
I borrowed from my relatives?
他真的能给吗
It's such a big real estate company,
毕竟这么大的地产公司
so it won't go bankrupt easily.
没有那么容易垮掉的
You can believe in the policy
再说了 你要相信政策
and the development of the industry.
和行业的发展啊
I wish I had taken your advice.
我当时听你的就好了
Here you are.
这个给你
The list of your clients?
你的客户名单啊
Yes. I've informed them all.
是的 我都打好招呼了
The client resources
这些客户资源啊
are left to you.
都留给你
Afterward, no matter
以后呢 不管你在
which company you are in,
哪一家地产公司
as long as you do a sales job,
只要你还做销售
you can use it.
都用得上
Keep those clients
你要好好维护
as hard as you can.
这些资源啊
Wanzhen,
姐
I can't thank you more.
真的太感谢你了
I used to be bad to you,
我之前对你那么不好
because I felt you were disguising.
我觉得你这人特装
I behaved like a jerk!
就处处针对你
But you are helping me
可你现在在我
in my hardest time
最难的时候
by giving me your clients!
你把你客户名单给我了
Thank you, Wanzhen.
谢谢婉真姐
Not at all, Feifei.
没关系啊 菲菲
You can learn from the failure.
你要吸取教训
As a real estate salesperson,
你是做地产销售的
you can't be professional enough
专业的人
to do a professional job.
就要干专业的事
Keep your clients.
好好维护客户吧
Thank you.
谢谢姐
It's so easy to be a good man!
当个好男人可真容易啊
Men don't need to deliver babies,
也不用生孩子
but a little bit of care
做点表面功夫
can gain them great praise.
别人就一顿夸
As for women,
当个女人呢
we take the risk
生孩子
of losing lives to deliver babies,
鬼门关走一遭
but are regarded as
还要被别人认为
unqualified moms by others.
不是个合格的好妈妈
Honey,
媳妇
do you really
那些话
believe in that?
你也真能听进去啊
I know that
那我老婆好不好
my wife is the best mom.
我心里最清楚了
Am I right, darling?
对吧 媳妇
Let me tell you
我跟你讲
why they praise me.
那些人为啥夸我
It's because we spent a lot of money.
那不是因为咱消费了吗
Xin,
心
when we left the hospital
这小西瓜
the time when our baby was one month old,
刚满月那会儿咱刚出院
you had not recovered yet.
你还没有恢复好呢
Now it's almost two months, right?
现在都快俩月了 是吧
I'd like to invite our parents
把爸妈都叫来
and give her a queen party!
我给她办个女王套餐
Really?
真的
I'll give Little Watermelon
给咱们家小西瓜
a full-month party.
补办一个满月派对
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样
Not good.
不怎么样
I don't expect the party.
办什么办呀
I'm dressed in pajamas every day.
我现在天天穿这个衣服
So ugly!
丑死了
That's easy.
这太简单了
I'll invite
给公司
the styling team
拍广告的造型团队
for my company's advertisement.
我给他请回来
I'll get you
我给你弄个
a floor-length gown as a queen,
英伦女皇大拖地长裙
and a big crown on your head.
给你弄个大王冠带着
I'll be your servant
我扶着你在全场
by holding your right hand.
给你演一个仆人
Dad will be the king,
咱爸国王
while Mom will be the queen.
咱妈王后
Meng'an can be the princess,
大姐长公主
Li Lin the Imperial son-in-law,
姐夫驸马爷
Yunjie a little princess,
云阶跟熊熊
and Xiongxiong a little prince.
格格跟皇阿哥
How's that?
怎么样
Not good.
不怎么样
What crap are you talking about?
这什么乱七八糟的
A floor-length gown?
什么大拖地长裙啊
A queen?
英伦女王啊
A big crown?
什么大王冠
An Imperial son-in-law?
一会儿又驸马爷
And a little princess?
格格的
Full of crap!
哪儿跟哪儿啊
Darling,
老婆
it's fashionable to
现在可流行的是
hold a mix-and-match party.
中西合璧 土洋结合
You're a mix-and-match product!
我看你就挺土的
They are our families.
都是自己人
Eating a cake
吃个蛋糕
would be enough.
吹个蜡烛行了
Is it a yes?
同意啦
Do it.
办去吧
Yes, Madam.
嗻
I'll go first.
走嘞 媳妇
The queen party!
女王套餐
Sir,
先生
we offer
我们提供
the basic party package.
基础的派对套餐
If you want to level it up,
如果您想要升级的话
you can refer to
可以参照一下
the price list.
这个价目表
Level it up.
必须升级
I'll buy
我办那个
Supreme Deluxe Party Package!
至尊豪华版派对套餐
Yes, Sir.
好的 先生
You're so good to your wife!
您对您妻子可真好
What a good man!
真是好男人
Of course. She deserves it.
那必须呀 我老婆特值
I admire your relationship.
你们也太恩爱了
Then, let me help you
那我就帮您
order this package.
订这款套餐了
Okay.
好
Sorry.
姑娘
Is there any package
还有没有更豪华
to be more deluxe?
更无敌的呢